profootballfocus.com 2012-06-15

# Privacy Statement | ProFootballFocus.com

This privacy policy sets out how ProFootballFocus.com uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

ProFootballFocus.com may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page regularly to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

  * This policy has been effective since 1st September 2008
  * This policy was last updated on 25th July 2011.

**1)** **What we collect**

In the course of using the Website, we may collect certain information from you, including:

**_1.1)_** ** _Information that you provide to us_**

  * Your name
  * contact information such as your mailing address, email address, phone number, or fax number
  * unique identifiers, such as your user ID, or user password

**_1.2)_** ** _Website Usage Information_**

We may receive and store certain types of internet usage information whenever you visit the Website, such as your IP address and click-stream data.

**_1.3)_** ** _Email Communications_**

When we send emails to you, we may receive a confirmation notifying us that you opened the email, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also may keep track of the emails you send us or we send you. Additionally, we keep a record of what communications you have selected to receive or not to receive. If you would like to opt-out of receiving such emails, please click on the “unsubscribe” link in the email and follow the instructions.

**2)** **How do we gather this data**

We collect data regarding you from the following sources:

**_2.1)_** ** _Registration_**

You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Website may choose to offer. Your decision to register is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to us.

**_2.2)_** ** _IP Addresses Click-Stream Data_**

We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data. In itself your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses for purposes of system administration and we may combine this information with personally identifiable information we obtain from you directly on the Website.

**_2.3)_** ** _Click-Stream Data_**

Click-stream data is information collected by us when you request pages from the Website. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Website, what type of content is most popular and the like.

**_2.4)_** ** _Transaction Information_**

**__** If you conduct a financial or other transaction with the Website, such as subscribe to a Subscription Product or other products/services offered on the Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information and/or financial information. In some instances, we may direct you to a third party vendor site to collect this information from you directly.  Please be aware you will be giving your information directly to the third party vendor, and that in some instances such third party vendor’s privacy policy will govern the collection of your personal information.  Please reference the privacy policies available from these pages for any privacy related concerns.

We and/or our vendor will use this information to complete the financial or other transaction that you have requested, i.e. to deliver the information, products or other services that you request or purchase and to invoice you in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.  For your protection, financial information is collected and stored through encrypted means.

**3)** **What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We would only contact you by email. We may use the information to customize the website according to your interests.
  * Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**4)** **How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**5)** **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**6)** **Controlling your personal information**

We do not reveal specific information about our customers to parties outside of our organization. It is for our independent use and will be disclosed only if you authorize it or the disclosure is otherwise lawfully permitted or required. We limit employee access to information to employees with a business reason to know that information. Our employees understand the importance of confidentiality, and we take appropriate steps to assure the integrity of the information we collect.

**7)** **Your Acceptance of this Privacy Policy**

By using the Website, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on the Website and / or send an email to users who have provided an email address. We will assume that you have given your permission for your information to be used under the terms of the Privacy Policy, as modified, if you do not respond to our email within thirty days or continue to use the Website thirty days after a notice is posted. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.
